Guide to the Charles Lewis Bowman photographs and drawings, 1917-1962
Bowman, Charles Lewis, photographs and drawings, 1917-1962
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Charles Lewis Bowman photographs and drawings, 1917-1962.
3807
Charles Lewis, Bowman 1890-1971.
8 cubic ft.
Photographs, drawings
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Photographs and architectural drawings of houses designed or altered by Charles Lewis Bowman.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Charles Lewis Bowman was an architect who designed many homes in Bronxville, New York and elsewhere.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Photographs and architectural drawings of houses designed or altered by Charles Lewis Bowman.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Bowman, Charles Lewis,1890-1971.
Subjects:
Architecture.; Architects.
Form and Genre Terms:
Drawings.; Photoprints.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Photographs
  Photographs of houses designed or altered by Lewis Bowman; the photographs are mainly the work of John Wallace Gillies ca. 1885-1927.
  - Bartlett, Edward R. - 512 Orchard Place, Bronxville, N.Y., 4 (Box 1)
  - Bates, E. E. - near Central Ave., Scarsdale, N.Y., 3 (Box 1)
  - Black, Charles - 14 Eastway, Bronxville, N.Y., 4 (Box 1)
  - Bliss, Julius - 21 Elm Rock Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 7 (Box 1)
  - Boardman, Phillip W., Jr.- 176 Old Bedford Road, Greenwich, Ct., 4; Includes digital copies on DVD-1070 and DVD-1071 (Box 7)
  - Bondy, Richard C. - Goldens Bridge, N.Y., 28 (Box 1)
  - Bowman, Mrs. Charles - 20 Oriole Ave., Bronxville, N.Y., 5 (Box 1)
  - Bowman, Lewis - Eastland and Esplanade, Pelham Hgts., N.Y., 5 (Box 1)
  - Bowman, Lewis - 136 Foster Ave., Mt. Vernon, N.Y., 8. (Box 1)
  - Bowman, Lewis - 330 Pondfield Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 4 (Box 1)
  - Bowman, Lewis - 5 Elm Rock Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 20 (Box 2)
  - Bowman, Milton S. - 15 Eastway, Bronxville, N.Y., 3 (Box 2)
  - Cloister Inn - Princeton, N.J., 7 (Box 2)
  - Corman, S. Wilbur - 5 Rittenhouse Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 6 (Box 2)
  - Eygaboard, Mrs. C. C. - 10 Hemlock Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 4 (Box 2)
  - Gibson, Charles R. - 3 Elm Rock Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 10 (Box 2)
  - Glorney, Miss Ethel M. - Manhhasset, L.I., 5 (Box 2)
  - Graham, Roy C. - 935 Kimball Ave., Bronxville, N.Y., 20 (Box 2)
  - Harvey, W. C. - Plainfield, N.J., 1 (Box 3)
  - Harwood, Frank - 247 Pondfield Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 13
    1 interior and 12 exterior 8" x 10" photograph
    - Interior: Living room with fireplace and furniture (Box 3)
    - Front of house with trees (Box 3)
    - Close up of front of house and living room window (Box 3)
    - Front door, glossy (Box 3)
    - Front door, matted print (Box 3)
    - Corner of house, driveway & schrubs (Box 3)
    - Rear of house from street (Box 3)
    - Rear driveway from street, gate open (Box 3)
    - Rear driveway from street, gate closed (Box 3)
    - Rear yard looking toward back doors (Box 3)
    - Rear yard looking toward closed gates and wall (Box 3)
    - Garden wall and door, glossy print (Box 3)
    - Garden wall and door, matted print (Box 3)
  - Harz, Alex - Beechmont Park, New Rochelle, N.Y., 2 (Box 3)
  - Hastings, Herbert - 15 Hawthorne Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 7 (Box 3)
  - Hellman, Richard - 54 Butler Rd., Scarsdale, N.Y., 11 (Box 3)
  - Impink, Irvin F. - Wyomissing Pk., Reading, Pa., 8 (Box 3)
  - Irving, A. J. - 5 Courseview Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 2 (Box 3)
  - Jewett, J. H. - Wood End Lane, Bronxville, N.Y., 2 (Box 3)
  - Jones, Robcliff V. - 6 Beechwood Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 19 (Box 3)
  - Kelly, Mrs. John T. - Heathcote Rd., near White Plains Rd. Scarsdale, N.Y., 7 (Box 3)
  - Kilburn, C. D. - Glen Ridge, N.J., 4 (Box 3)
  - Leinbach, Henry M. - Wyomissing Pk., Reading, Pa., 6 (Box 3)
  - Maltby, Ralph B. - 31 Masterton Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 9 (Box 3)
  - McDonald, D. G. - 8 Eastway, Bronxville, N.Y., 16 (Box 4)
  - McKee, Neal T. - 19 Return Bend Lane, Bronxville, N.Y., 9 (Box 4)
  - McKee or Hastings (same#'s as Kilburn) -, 3 (Box 4)
  - Morden, William J. - 47 Masterton Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 7 (Box 4)
  - Morse, Henry N. - 9 Elm Rock Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 16 (Box 4)
  - Ohrstrom, George L - Old Mill Rd., Greenwich, Ct., 18 (Box 4)
  - Peck, Albert - 41 Masterton Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 1 (Box 4)
  - Pennell, Henry Beaumont - 33 Elm Rock Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 5 (Box 4)
  - Quantrell, Ernest E. - 5 Leonard Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 3 (Box 4)
  - Roebling, Robert C. - Lawrenceville, N.J., 23 (Box 5)
  - Schaff, Frederick - 27 Masterton Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 20 (Box 5)
  - Slattery, John J. - 16 Eastway, Bronxville, N.Y., 4 (Box 5)
  - Streat, Herbert G. - 8 Elm Rock Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 9 (Box 5)
  - Troxell, Edward - Beechwood Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 4 (Box 5)
  - Van Patten, L. A. - Pelham Hgts., N.Y., 2 (Box 5)
  - Wardv Benjamin I. - Englewood, N.J., 8 (Box 5)
  - Weihman, Clifford T. - 401 Monterey Ave., Pelham Manor, N.Y., 5 (Box 5)
  - Whitfield, George P. - 27 Hampshire Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 3 (Box 5)
  - Wilkin, Ray T. - 9 Beechwood Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 6 (Box 5)
  - 1 print Christopher Wren, 1 (Box 6)
  - Unidentified, or partially identified, photographs
    - 5 Orchard Place # B5189-91, 3 (Box 6)
    - Pelham, N.Y. # 727069, -74, 2 (Box 6)
    - Unidentified # 1509-1, 1 (Box 6)
    - Unidentified # 1542, 2 (Box 6)
    - Unidentified # 1543, 1 (Box 6)
    - Unidentified # 1544, 1 (Box 6)
    - Unidentified # 1546, 2 (Box 6)
    - Unidentified # 1614, 3 (Box 6)
  - Assorted 8 x 10 photographs of Bowman architecture prepared for publication in "Your Home", 1952. [35 duplicates, 2 not duplicates, per H. Applegate. 1-28-81], 37 (Box 6)
  - Volume Monographie du Palais de Compeigne Meuble, Bronzes, Decorations (Box 6)
  - Volume Monographie du Muses de Cluny Epoques: Gothique, Renaissance, Louis XIII a Louis XVI (Box 6)
  - Photo with overlay showing location of houses built by Lewis Bowman and map of Bronxville area (Box 6)
  - Thesis: Lewis Bowman and the Jacobethan Revival by Peter Flagg Maxson, May, 1975. (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous photos, negatives, real estate advertising material. (Box 7-8)
- Series II. Architectural Drawings
  - Job #135/ Starkey, J.F. (alteration to)/ 67 Prospect St., White Plains, N.Y., 1921; 7 (Folder 1)
  - Job #138/ Duff, J.E./ Pelham, N.Y. (on the West side of Pelhamdale Ave. near First Street), 1921; 5 (Folder 1)
  - Job #140/ not identified/, n. d.; 7 (Folder 1)
  - Job #141/ Gillespie, Gardiner F./ Short Hills, N.J., n.d.; 7 (Folder 2)
  - Job #144/ Herz, Rudolph/ New Rochelle, N.Y. (Overlook Circle Beechmont Lot 13), n.d.; 8 (Folder 2)
  - Job #151/ White, T.J./ Woodmere, L.I., 1923; 10 (Folder 2)
  - Job #154/ Clarke, H.W./ Bronxville, N.Y., 1923; 13 (Folder 3)
  - Job #172/ "Residence #46 for the Westchester Improvement Co. " "Residence for the Bomnar Development Corp. "/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1923; 12 (Folder 3)
  - Job #173/ Ellison, N.D./ Burkewood Rd, Mt. Vernon, N.Y., 1924; 10 (Folder 4)
  - Job #174/ Warren, F.H./ Douglaston, L.I., 1924; 8 (Folder 4)
  - Job #175/ Troxell, F.R./ Bronxville, N.Y., 1924; 8 (Folder 4)
  - Job #180/ Russell, Mrs. Ellen M./ Bronxville, N.Y., 1924; 8 (Folder 5)
  - Job #181/ Greene, H.C./ Bronxville, N.Y., 1924; 8 (Folder 5)
  - Job #217/ Bister, F.J./ Larchmont, N.Y., 1925; 7 (Folder 5)
  - Job #228/ O'Loughlin,/ Bronxville, N.Y. (also Lot Survey), 1926; 10 (Folder 6)
  - Job #231/ Harvey, W.C. (alteration to)/ Plainfield, N.J., 1926; 6 (Folder 6)
  - Job #232/ Clark, W.F./ Bronxville, N.Y. ("I think never built"), 1926; 9 (Folder 7)
  - Job #233/ Foster, A.C./ New Rochelle, N.Y., 1926; 7 (Folder 7)
  - Job #234/ Lerner, Samuel A.(Garage)/ Mt. Vernon, N.Y., 1926; 3 (Folder 8)
  - Job #235/ (mostly rough drawings)/ Island Park, Long Beach, L.I., 1926; 10 (Folder 8)
  - Job #236/ Tiso, Mrs. Clementine/ Mt. Vermont, N.Y. (No street address), 1926; 6 (Folder 9)
  - Job #241/ Longo, Sam/ Pelham, N.Y. (also Lot Survey Certificate "Hutchinson Manor"), 1926; 5 (Folder 9)
  - Job #250/ Kerin, Thomas F./ Scarsdale, N.Y., 1927; 5 (Folder 9)
  - Job #251/ Eygabroad, Mrs. C.L./ Bronxville, N.Y., 1927; 16 (Folder 10)
  - Job #252/ Mendes, H.E./ Mamaroneck, N.Y., 1927; 9 (Folder 11)
  - Job #258/ Stillman, A.F./ Bronxville, N.Y., n.d.; 8 (Folder 11)
  - Job #261/ / Rittenhouse Rd., near California Rd. Eastchester, N.Y., 1928; 7 (Folder 12)
  - Job #281/ Chiaholm, Charles B./ Scarsdale, N.Y., 1929; 6 (Folder 12)
  - Job #283/ Quantrell, E.E. (alteration to)/ Bronxville/ N.Y., 1929; 6 (Folder 12)
  - Job #286/ Vigneron, E.M./ Larchmont, N.Y., 1929; 7 (Folder 13)
  - Job #326/ Wellman, Guy/ Chappaqua, N. Y., 1935; 9 (Folder 13)
  - Job #355/ Lathrop, Mr. and Mrs. Walter/ Mystic, Ct., 1946; 13 (Folder 13)
  - Alterations to Residence of Mr. and Mrs. Frank C. McLearn, 48 Prescott Ave., Bronxville, N.Y., April 10, 1957 (1 packet of 4 drawings, donated by Mrs. Frank C. McLearn, Feb. 1980) (Folder 14)
  - Job #118A/ Albert Bradley (alteration to)/ Mayfair Lane, Greenwich, Ct., 1938; 9 (Folder 15)
  - Job #112A/ /, 1938; 5 (Folder 15)
  - Job #(20/ original plans by Twachtman for l18A)/, 1929; 6 (Folder 15)
  - Job #119A/ Charles MacArthur (alt. to farm house) / Tallmans, N.Y., 1938 3; .2 (Folder 15)
  - Job #139/ Elderwood Ave., Pelham Hgts., N.Y/ lots 218-220-222, n.d.; 4 (Folder 15)
  - Job #158/ N.T. McKee/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1923; 8 (Folder 16)
  - Job #158A/ Sinclair Lewis (addition to)/ Bronxville, N.Y., n.d.; 5 (Folder 16)
  - Job #165/ Mrs. Lewis Bowman/ cnr. Foster Ave. and Grand St., lot 241 (Folder 16)
  - Job #/ / Mt. Vernon, N.Y. (Gramaton Homes, Inc.), 1917; 3 (Folder 16)
  - Job #170/ Russell C. Jones (alt. to)/ Elm Rock Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 1923; 5 (Folder 16)
  - Job #170/ (add. to)/, 1928; 1 (Folder 16)
  - Job #176/ / cnr. Oriole Ave, and Elm Rock Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 1924; 8 (Folder 17)
  - Job #176A/ E.B. Pennell (revised)/ cnr. Oriole Ave. and Elm Rock Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 1930; 8 (Folder 17)
  - Job #182/ E.R. Bartlett/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1924; 6 (Folder 17)
  - Job #190/ R.C. Graham/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1924; 8 (Folder 18)
  - Job #192/ F.A. Schaff/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1924; 9 (Folder 18)
  - Job #196/ / Masterton Rd., nr. Pondfield Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 1924; 8 (Folder 18)
  - Job #198/ R.V. Jones/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1924; 8 (Folder 19)
  - Job #(186)/ (proposed rev.)/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1931; 6 (Folder 19)
  - Job #198A/ (alt. to)/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1931; 7 (Folder 19)
  - Job #197/ / Pondfield Rd. nr. Masterton Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 1925; 7 (Folder 20)
  - Job #197/ (alt. to)/ Pondfield Rd. nr. Masterton Rd., Bronxville, N.Y., 4 (Folder 20)
  - Job #202/ F. Irving Hull/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1924; 9 (Folder 20)
  - Job #219/ J.J. Slattery/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1925; 6 (Folder 25)
  - Job #225/ Miss Ethel M. Glorney/ Plandome, L.I., 1925; 8 (Folder 25)
  - Job #226/ / Eastway nr. Northway, Bronxville, N.Y., 1926; 7 (Folder 25)
  - Job #229/ R.B. Maltby/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1926; 6 (Folder 25)
  - Job #237/ H.M. Leinbach/ Reading, Pa., 1926; 7 (Folder 26)
  - Job #238/ Albert C. Ayre/ Scarsdale, N.Y., 1926; 6 (Folder 26)
  - Job #242/ R.C. Bondy/ Goldensbridge, N.Y., 1927; 7 (Folder 27)
  - Job #245/ T.H. VanNess/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1926; 6 (Folder 28)
  - Job #247/ S.W. Noyes/ Dobbs Ferry, N.Y., 1927; 7 (Folder 28)
  - Job #247A/ S.W. Noyes (cottage)/ Dobbs Ferry, N.Y., 1928; 7 (Folder 28)
  - Job #249/ Mrs. Harriet Skipwith/ Bronxville, N.J., 1927; 8 (Folder 29)
  - Job #253/ E. DeGolyer/ Montclair, N.J., 1927; 9 (Folder 29)
  - Job #254/ L.J. Plumb/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1927; 8 (Folder 30)
  - Job #255/ I.F. Impink/ Reading, Pa., 1927; 8 (Folder 31)
  - Job #256/ George L. Ohrstrom/ 124 Old Mill Road, Greenwich, Ct., 1927; 9 (Folder 31)
  - Job #256B/ George L. Ohrstrom (Community House)/ Greenwich, Ct., 1929; 7 (Folder 31)
  - Job #262/ Julius Bliss/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1928; 7 (Folder 32)
  - Job #264/ D.G. McDonald/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1928; 8 (Folder 32)
  - Job #273/ Mabel H. Wallace/ Scarsdale, N.Y., 1928; 8 (Folder 33)
  - Job #273/ F.W. Wallace/ Scarsdale, N.Y., 1923; 6 (Folder 33)
  - Job #282/ L.M. Goodever/ Scarsdale, N.Y., 1929; 13 (Folder 33)
  - Job #284/ Ralph L. Baldwin/ Quogue, L.I., 1929; 9 (Folder 34)
  - Job #285/ Mrs. John T. Kelly/ Scarsdale, N.Y., 1929; 8 (Folder 34)
  - Job #288/ Lewis Bowman/ Westhampton Bch., L.I., 1930; 8 (Folder 34)
  - Job #295/ Mrs. Clement A. Griscom/ Riverdale-on-Hudson, N.Y., 1930; 11 (Folder 35)
  - Job #295A/ Mrs. Clement A. Griscom (gatehouse)/ Riverdale-on-Hudson, N.Y., 1930; 4 (Folder 35)
  - Job #300/ Mrs. Eleanor Bowman/ Eastchester, N.Y., 1930; 6 (Folder 36)
  - Job #301\/ Mrs. Eleanor Bowman/ Eastchester, N.Y., 1930; 14 (Folder 36)
  - Job #302/ Bowman/ Eastchester, N.Y., 1930; 6 (Folder 36)
  - Job #303/ Viking Building Corp./ Eastchester, N.Y., 1930; 6 (Folder 36)
  - Job #308/ Gustav Oberlander (museum)/ Reading, Pa., 1931; 6 (Folder 37)
  - Job #314/ Alfred H. Ericson/ Lawrence Park West, Yonkers, N.Y. (EHB: never built), 1931; 7 (Folder 37)
  - Job #315/ Alfred H. Ericson/ Lawrence Park West, Yonkers, N.Y. (EHB: never built), 1932; 7 (Folder 37)
  - Job #316/ Richard Hellmann/ Scarsdale, N.Y., 1932; 10 (Folder 38)
  - Job #318/ Frank Nilan/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1932; 7 (Folder 38)
  - Job #319/ Arch. B. Campbell/ Eastchester, N.Y., 1933; 9 (Folder 39)
  - Job #319/ Arch. B. Campbell/ Eastchester, N.Y., 1936; 10 (Folder 39)
  - Job #321/ Mrs. Mary Schelberg/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1934; 6 (Folder 39)
  - Job #323/ Mrs. Robert S. Byfield/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1934; 13 (Folder 40)
  - Job #330/ /, 1935 (Folder 40)
  - Job #(330)/ Walter Free/, 7 (Folder 40)
  - Job #330/ Walter Free/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1939; 8 (Folder 40)
  - Job #332/ George Morris/ Catrock Rd., Greenwich, Ct., 1936; 7 (Folder 41)
  - Job #333/ (layout by Fitzgibbons Boiler Co,)/, 1936; 3 (Folder 41)
  - Job #333/ Jack Johns ton/ Greenwich, Ct., 1936; 7 (Folder 41)
  - Job #339/ L. Boyd Hatch/ Providence, Utah (Residence, guest cottage, gardener's cottage, gateways), 1938-1945; 39 (Folder 42)
  - Job #/ L. Boyd Hatch / Mt. Airey, N.J. (living room entrance on Farm), 1 (Folder 42)
  - Job #340/ William S. Johnston/ Scarsdale, N.Y., 1938; 16 (Folder 43)
  - Job #342/ Mrs. Charles MacArthur / Wesley Chapel, N.Y. (garage on farm), 1938; 9 (Folder 43)
  - Job #342/ Mrs. Charles MacArthur / Westley Chapel, N.Y. (stable and barn of farm group), 1941; 6 (Folder 43)
  - Job #344/ Philip W. Boardman, Jr./ Greenwich, Ct., 1942; 21; Includes digital copies on DVD-1070 and DVD-1071 (Box 7)
  - Job #352/ Philip L. Bondy/ Salem Center, N.Y., 1945-1947; 8 (Folder 43)
  - Job #354/ Mr. and Mrs. Howard Y. Broek/ Bronxville, N.Y. (also 2 copies of specifications- 15 pages ea.), 1946; 8 (Folder 43)
  - Job #/ Theodore W. Cart/ Harbourton, N.J., 1957; 21 (Folder 44)
  - Job #/ H.W. Dodge/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1936; 13 (Folder 44)
  - Job #/ Morris Feinberg / 136 Foster Ave, Mt. Vernon, N.Y. (porch), 1944; 1 (Folder 44)
  - Job #/ Mr. and Mrs. F.M. Flynn/ Pelham Manor, N.Y., 1953, 1954; 29 (Folder 45)
  - Job #/ Mr. and Mrs. Richard Hellmann/ Harrison, N.Y., 1953; 14 (Folder 46)
  - Job #/ Louis Kallish / 50 Syracome Ave, Mt. Vernon, N.Y. (porch and Studio), 1946; 2 (Folder 46)
  - Job #,r// Mr. and Mrs. Frank C. McLearn/ Prescott Ave, Bronxville, N.Y., 1949; 12 (Folder 46)
  - Job #/ Mr. and Mrs. Leonard Marx/ Scarsdale, N.Y., 1962; 15 (Folder 46)
  - Job #/ Mr. and Mrs. George Ohrstrom/ The Plains, Va., 1950; 19 (Folder 47)
  - Job #/ Mr. and Mrs. Kimpton Rogers/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1953; 12 (Folder 47)
  - Job #/ Dr.. and. Mrs. Harold Spencer/ Ossining, N.Y., 1950; 1 (Folder 47)
  - Job #/ Mr. and Mrs. Roy Stephens/ Bronxville, N.Y., 1951; 8 (Folder 47)
  - Job #/ unidentified and miscellaneous including those of lanterns/, 11 (Folder 48)